Guide to the James Hartshorne collection, 1966-1994
Hartshorne, James collection
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
James Hartshorne collection, 1966-1994
4751
Hartshorne, James.
3.4 cubic feet.
Correspondence, Memorabilia, Printed Materials
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes correspondence and records pertaining to various track meets and events, including track meet results, workout schedules and memorabilia.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
Hartshorne was a competitive nationally ranked master's runner, an expert in exercise physiology, one of the founding members of the Finger Lakes Runners Club and the Finger Lakes Cycling Club, the creator of the Cornell Masters Mile and the race director for twenty years. The event was renamed The Hartshorne Masters Mile. He promoted Masters-level competition in track and field on the east coast, especially the masters mile.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes correspondence and records pertaining to various track meets and events, including track meet results, workout schedules and memorabilia.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Hartshorne, James; Cornell Masters Mile.; Finger Lakes Cycling Club.; Finger Lakes Runners Club.
Subjects:
Running.; Running--Training.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Constitution/Bylaws/Organization, 1978-1981 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Track: FLRC: AAU Misc., 1968-1971 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- FLRC: Insurance- RRCA Master Plan, Records, Forms, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Track: FLRC History, 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- FLRC Year End Report, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- FLRC: Complex Origins, by Catherine Frechehe, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Track: FLRC Membership Lists, 1969-1977 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- FLRC: Directory, 1979-1991 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Ballots, 1970-1978 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- FLRC: Finances, Check Register, 1970-1980 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Financial, 1980-1983 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- FLRC: Paid Receipts, 1979-1991 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- FLRC: Logo & Club Designs, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Track: FLRC Announcements to Club Members, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Annual Club Banquet, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Track: FLRC Courses, Misc., 1973-1979 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Track: Measurement of Road Courses, 1971-1977 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Track: Appreciation, Letters of, 1973-1986 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- FLRC: Correspondence, 1979-1992 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Track: US Masters Correspondence, 1968-1972 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Track: FLRC Correspondence, 1968-1970 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Track: Correspondence, Misc., 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Track: FLRC Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Track: Correspondence, Misc., 1972-1991 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Track: FLRC Correspondence, 1973-1979 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Track: FLRC Originals Courses & Maps, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- FLRC: Clothing Inventory, 1973-1982 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- FLRC meet Results, 1968-1982 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Track: FLRC Meet Results, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Track: FLRC Meet Results (Mimeo’d Copies), 1970 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Track: FLRC Meet Results (Mimeo’d Copies), 1971 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Track: FLRC Meet Results, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Track: FLRC Meet Results, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Track: FLRC Meet Results, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Track: FLRC Meet Results, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Track: FLRC Meet Results, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Track: FLRC Meet Results, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Track: FLRC Meet Results, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Track: FLRC Meet Results, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Track: FLRC Photos, 1969-1971 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Track: FLRC Awards & AW. Sched (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Jim Hartshorne Death Notices, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Track: FLRC Newsletter, 1970-1978 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Track: FLRC “One Hour Run”, 1973-1980 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Track Originals Club Org. Duties, Assign., 1970 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Track: FLRC Originals Meet Forms, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Track: FLRC Originals Misc., 1969-1980 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Track: FLRC Originals Meet Results, 1968-1979 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Track: FRLC – Publicity, 1975-1979 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Track: FLRC Press & Radio Releases, 1968-1975 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Track: FLRC Year-END Reports, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Track: FLRC Press Write-UPS, 1969-1980 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- FLRC: Performances of Members, 1970-1977 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Track: FLRC 12-minute Run, 1974-1981 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- 5&10: Finances, 1975-1981 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- 5 & 10: Info. To residents along course, 1975-1982 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Results – Misc., 1979-1987 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- 5&10: Entry Blanks, 1975-1982 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- 5&10 Ithaca, 1975-1983 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- 5&10: T-Shirts, 1975-1983 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- 5&10: Post-Meet Follow up, 1975-1979 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- 5&10: Permits / Sanctions, 1975-1979 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- 5&10: Publicity – Premeet, 1975-1979 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- 5&10: results, Summ. Past Yrs., 1975-1979 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- 5&10: Misc., 1976 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- 5&10: Info to runners, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Info to explorers, police, sheriff’s deputies, 1977-1979 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- 5&10: Publicity – Post Meet, 1979-1982 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- 5&10: Post-Mortem Suggested changes &/or additions, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- 5&10: Correspondence, 1975-1979 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- 5&10: Premeet Organization, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- 5&10: Course Layout & Measurement Originals & Reductions, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- 5&10: Originals, 1975-1980 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- 5&10: Awards, 1975-1980 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Finger Lakes Cycling Club, 1980-1984 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- C-N-S-C (Cayuga Nordic Ski Club), 1985-1988 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Cayuga Nordic Ski Club Newsletter, 1988-1983 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Track: HEPS Masters Mile Photos, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Track: HEPS Masters Mile Misc., 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Track: HEPS Masters Mile Publicity: Press, etc., 1961-1971 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Track: HEPS Masters Mile Programs, 1969-1976 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Track: HEPS, Masters Mile Originals, 1969-1977 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Track: HEPS Masters Mile Mimeo’d Data – Copies, 1969-1974 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Track: HEPS Masters Mile Correspondence, 1969-1976 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Track: HEPS Masters Mile Entries, 1973-1977 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- MM: Starters List (for program), 1970-1987 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- MM: Results – XX Year Summaries, 1968-1987 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- MM: Finances/Finance Statements, 1969-1987 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- MM: Awards (orders/receipts), 1969-1987 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- MM: Originals, 1969-1987 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Masters Mile, 1992-1994 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- MM: Awards Dinner/Reception, 1972-1985 (Box 2, Folder 45)
- MM: Master Check-List, 1974-1987 (Box 2, Folder 46)
- MM: Programs, 1968-1990 (Box 2, Folder 47)
- Boston Alternative Marathon, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 48)
- Boston Qualifier, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 49)
- Track, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 50)
- BQ, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 51)
- Road Rage 1979, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 52)
- BQ, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 53)
- Track: FLRC Boston Qualifier, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Track: FLRC Boston Qualifier, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Track: FLRC Boston Qualifier, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Track: FLRC Boston Qualifier, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Track: FLRC Boston Qualifier, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Track: FLRC Boston Qualifier, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Track: Boston Qualifier Marathon Misc. Useful Info., 1978-1982 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Track: FLRC Boston Qualifier Correspondence, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Track: FLRC Boston Qualifier Info to Participants, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Track: FLRC Boston Qualifier Course Maps, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- FLM, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- FLM, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Finger Lakes Marathon Press Write-ups, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Track: Finger Lakes Marathon Press Write-ups, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Track: Finger Lakes Marathon Press Write-ups, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- FLM Press Clippings, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Track: Finger Lakes Marathon Press Write-ups, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Track: Finger Lakes Marathon Press write-ups, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Track: Finger Lakes Marathon Press write-ups, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Track: Finger Lakes Marathon Press Write-ups, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- FLM: Timers/Recordings/Sweeps Schedule & Instructions (Box 3, Folder 21)
- FLM: Results, Past Years, 1973-1993 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Track: Finger Lakes Marathon Press & Radio Releases, 1970-1978 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- FLM: Publicity- Running Magazines, 1970-1979 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- FLM: Post-Meet Follow-up, 1970-1979 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- FLM: Originals, 1970-1979 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- FLM: Awards, 1970-1989 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- FLM: Correspondence, 1970-1988 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- FLM: Publicity – Press/Radio, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- FLM: Race Day – Check List & Misc., 1979 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Press & Radio Releases for FLM, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- FLM: T-Shirts, 1979-1984 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- FLM: Appreciation, Note of, 1977-1979 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- FLM: Finances, 1973-1979 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- FLM: Pre-meet Organization, 1970-1981 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- FLM: MAPS, Race Course (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Track: Finger Lakes Marathon Certificates (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Track: Finger Lakes Marathon Photos (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Weights & Weight Training, 1990-94 (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Sports: Skiing, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 40)
- Sailing, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 41)
- Sports: Equipment, 1965-1994 (Box 3, Folder 42)
- Sports: Skating, 1969-1983 (Box 3, Folder 43)
- Masters T&&, 1988-1993 (Box 3, Folder 44)
- Running Articles, 1978-1980 (Box 3, Folder 45)
- Track: AAU.Info., 1974-1976 (Box 3, Folder 46)
- Track: Announcements & Entry Blacks, Track, Road Race& XC, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 47)
- Track: Announcements, Masters, Meets, Road Races & XC, 1977-1980 (Box 3, Folder 48)
- Track: Articles: Over-40 Running & The Masters Mile – DNR, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 49)
- Track: Articles- Over 40 Running, 1969-87 (Box 3, Folder 50)
- Track: Articles, 1968-1984 (Box 3, Folder 51)
- Senior Games, 1991-93 (Box 3, Folder 52)
- Track: Boston Marathon, 1971-1993 (Box 3, Folder 53)
- Track: Cornell, 1942-1990 (Box 3, Folder 54)
- Track: Hornell “7 Mile Road Race”, 1968-1976 (Box 3, Folder 55)
- Track: Course Map, B,A,A, Marathon Drawn by: F.K. Moore, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 56)
- Track: Masters Sports Assoc., 1971-1974 (Box 3, Folder 57)
- Track: 1974 Meets Attended, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 58)
- Track: 1973 Meets Attended, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 59)
- Track: 1972 Meets Attended, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 60)
- Track: 1971 Meets Attended, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 61)
- Track: 1970 Meets Attended, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 62)
- Track: 1969 Meets Attended, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 63)
- Track: 1969 Meets Attended, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 64)
- Track: Mass K of C, Press Releases, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 65)
- Track: 1968 Meets Attended, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 66)
- Track: 1967 Meets Attended, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 67)
- Track: 1966 Meets Attended, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 68)
- Track: Newsletters: Misc. Clubs, 1970-1981 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Track: Misc., 1965-1987 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Track: Newsletter: Princeton, 1972-1978 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Track: Newsletter: Triple Cities R.C., 1971-1977 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Track: Newsletter: Syracuse Chargers, 1977-81 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Track: Phili Masters Track Assoc., 1972-1974 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Track: Newsletter: Seniors T.C. (L.A. area), 1970-1973 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Track: Organizations, Memberships, etc., 1968-1994 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Track: Photos, 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Track: Podiatrists, Sports Med. List of in U.S.A., 1983-1991 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Track: E.R. Drinks & Food Supply, 1973-1993 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Track: Results, Masters Championship Events, 1972-1975 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Track: results, Masters Events, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Track: Results, Masters Events, 1966-1972 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Track: Rochester Road Runners Club, 1967-1976 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Track: 1st US masters T&F Meet Miscellaneous, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Track: Springbank Road Races, 1969-1977 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Running: Shoes, 1981-1994 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Workout Schedule, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Track/Cycling: Workout Schedules, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Track/Cycling: Workout Schedules, 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Track/Cycling: Workout Schedules, 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Track: Workout Schedules, 1967-1969 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Track Workouts & Meets, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 24)